Guide to the John O'Toole Papers, 1954-1990 and undated RL.00983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John O'Toole papers
1954-1990 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
O'Toole, John E.
RL.00983
23 Linear Feet
John O'Toole (1929-1995) was an American advertising executive who served as Chairman of Foote, Cone & Belding, Inc. (FCB) from 1981-1985. He also served as President of the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA) from 1988-1995. The John O'Toole Papers cover the years 1954-1990, with the bulk of materials dating from the 1980s, roughly the period when O'Toole served as Chairman of Foote, Cone & Belding (FCB), and as an executive with the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA). The collection primarily consists of correspondence; speeches; research reports; business presentations; and slides related to FCB management and advertising activities. The collection also includes several proofs; clippings; and a film of television advertisements for Merrill Lynch. Advertisers represented in the collection include British Airways; Clairol; Colgate-Palmolive; Frito-Lay; Gillette; Heinz; Jockey; Pepsi; Sunkist; and Volkswagen. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
17250 Items
Access Restrictions
RESTRICTED: Files relating to the employment history of individuals other than John O'Toole are closed for 25 years from the date of the individual employee's death, or 40 years from the date of termination if the date of death cannot be determined.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron access until use copies can be made.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John O'Toole Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1995 and 1996.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1929 Born, Chicago, Ill.
1951 BA, Journalism, Northwestern University
1951-1953 U.S. Marine Corps Reserves
1953-1954 Copy Writer, Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn
1954 Copy Writer, Foote, Cone & Belding Communications, Inc. (FCB)
1965 Creative Director, FCB's Los Angeles Office.
1967 Creative Director, FCB's Chicago Office.
1969-1981 President, FCB's New York Office.
1981 Published book The Trouble with Advertising.
1981-1985 Chairman of FCB, Inc.
1986-1988 Director, American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA).
1988-1995 President, AAAA.
1995 Died.
During his adolescent years, John O'Toole wrote several plays for a local radio station and over 200 poems for newspapers, magazines and anthologies. At age 18, one of his books of poetry was published; the proceeds from this publication paid for his first year of college.
O'Toole worked as a waiter, radio announcer and meter reader before beginning a career in the advertising business. O'Toole's first advertising job was for Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, where he served as copywriter on the accounts Royal Crown Cola, Ac'cent, and Amity Leather Products. In 1954, he joined the staff of Foote, Cone & Belding (FCB), where he began as Copy Writer and subsequently became Copy Supervisor, Vice President, Creative Director of the Los Angeles and Chicago offices. During his career, he wrote copy and campaign themes for more than 40 television commercials. Some of his major clients included the First National Bank of Chicago, Kimberly-Clark Corporation, General Foods, Armour Soap Works and Kraft Foods.
O'Toole also served prominently in the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA), as Director and then President of the Association. He also served as Director of the National Advertising Review Council, and served on the Board of Directors of John Nuveen Mutual Funds.
Collection Overview
The John O'Toole Papers cover the years 1954-1990, with the bulk of materials dating from the 1980s, roughly the period when O'Toole served as Chairman of Foote, Cone & Belding (FCB), and as an executive with the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA). The collection primarily consists of correspondence; speeches; research reports; business presentations; and slides related to FCB management and advertising activities. The collection also includes several proofs; clippings; and a film of television advertisements for Merrill Lynch. Advertisers represented in the collection include British Airways; Clairol; Colgate-Palmolive; Frito-Lay; Gillette; Heinz; Jockey; Pepsi; Sunkist; and Volkswagen.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 13 series: Administrative Files; American Association of Advertising Agencies Files; Client Files; Correspondence; International Offices; Meetings; New Business; Personnel; Reports; Slides; Writings and Speeches; Audiovisual Materials; and Oversize Materials. The Administrative Files Series consists of administrative records, clippings, company promotional materials, printed matter, memorabilia, budgets, organizational information, expense records, and files related to various FCB programs and initiatives. The American Association of Advertising Agencies Files Series contains correspondence, meeting programs, itineraries, presentations and minutes, as well as research materials and reports from the period during which O'Toole served as Director of the AAAA. The Client Files Series contains presentations, correspondence, reports, charts, proofs and tearsheets for domestic and international FCB clients. The Correspondence Series contains O'Toole's personal and business correspondence, including office-wide memoranda, including those sent by O'Toole while he was company Chairman and several folders of carbon copies. The International Offices Series contains reports, correspondence, and organizational information related to the operations of FCB's international offices. The Meetings Series contains correspondence, memoranda, agendas, minutes, reports, presentation scripts, and other documents relating to meetings of FCB staff and of various advertising organizations. Also includes files related to luncheons and dinners of FCB staff, advertising organizations and various societies outside of the advertising business. The New Business Series contains materials related to the attempts of FCB to acquire new accounts, primarily including drafts and scripts of general agency presentations designed for prospective clients. The Reports Series contains reports and charts covering topics such as advertising techniques, research, media, industries, and demographics. Also includes annual reports, operations reviews and creative reviews for company-wide performance. The Slides Series contains slides of advertisements for FCB and competing agencies. The Writings and Speeches Series contains primarily speeches written and delivered by O'Toole, relating to various advertising topics. Includes some speeches and articles written by other FCB staff or other advertising professionals. The Audiovisual Materials Series includes a 16mm reel of advertisements presented at a World Creative Directors' Conference, a 16mm reel of advertising spots for Merrill Lynch, and an audiotape of a recording of the song Quick Changes, to which John O'Toole wrote the lyrics. The Oversize Materials Series includes large-format items removed from previous series.
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Materials relating to the American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA):
American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA) Records
Materials relating to the Foote, Cone & Belding agency:
Arthur Einstein Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising Vertical File
J. Walter Thompson Company. Colin Dawkins Papers
John E. Brennan Outdoor Advertising Survey Reports
The Papers of other advertising Creative Directors:
Gene Federico Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Wallace W. Elton Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Edgar Hatcher Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Bertram Metter Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. George Black Papers
Kensinger Jones Papers
David B. McCall Papers
Charles McKinney Papers
Lore Parker Papers
Joel Raphaelson Papers
Anthony Weir Papers
Advertising agencies -- United States; Slides (photographs); Audiotapes; 16mm; Advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Advertising executives -- United States; British Airways; Clairol, inc.; Colgate-Palmolive Company; Foote, Cone & Belding; American Association of Advertising Agencies; O'Toole, John E.; Sunkist Growers, Inc.; PepsiCo, Inc.; Volkswagenwerk; Merrill Lynch & Co. (1973-); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; O'Toole, John E.; Gillette Company; Frito-Lay, Inc.; Jockey International; H.J. Heinz Company
- Administrative Files, 1954-1988 and undated, 4 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of administrative records, clippings, company promotional materials, printed matter, memorabilia, budgets, organizational information, expense records, and files related to various FCB programs and initiatives. Folder titles maintained and items arranged alphabetically.
  - Bipartisan Budget, 1983-1984, 3 folders (Box 1)
    [Some items removed to oversize.]
  - Bipartisan Budget packet, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
  - Car limo service, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - Claude Award ballots, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Company archives, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Company history, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Corporate apartment, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Creative Service Control Department, Creative Work Procedures, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Credit cards, undated (Box 1)
  - Direct Response, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Employee Handbook, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Entertainment, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Expense Reports, 1981-1983, 1-2 of 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Expense Reports, 1981-1983 (continued), 3-7 of 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Expense Reports, 1984-1985, 1-4 of 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Expense Reports, 1984-1985 (continued), 5 of 5 folders (Box 3)
  - FCB Management Philosophies, 1983 (Box 3)
  - FCB Telecom, 1981-1982, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Information Center, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Interviews, general, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Legal, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, 1952-1969 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, 1970-1982, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - New York Office
    - Organization, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Relocation Factbook, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Space Planning, 1981 (Box 3)
  - New York Profit Management Committee, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Northwestern University Field Study Program, 1982 Jul. 26 (Box 3)
  - O'Toole personal files, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - O'Toole stationery, undated (Box 3)
  - Printed matter
    - Global Marketing Materials, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters, Chicago Office, 1954-1958 (Box 3)
    - Person to Person Magazine, 1977-1985, 1-2 of 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Person to Person Magazine, 1977-1985 (continued), 3-4 of 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Public relations, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Public relations plans, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Public service contributions, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Resumé, undated (Box 4)
  - Song writing, undated (Box 4)
  - Stockholders, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Today Show appearance, 1981 Dec. 11 (Box 4)
  - Transportation, limo proposal, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Travel and entertainment, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Video conferences, 1981 (Box 4)
  - William vs. FCB
    - General files, 1982-1984 (Box 4)
    - O'Toole deposition, 1984 (Box 4)
- American Association of Advertising Agencies Files, 1980-1986 and undated, 5 boxes
  Contains correspondence, meeting programs, itineraries, presentations and minutes, as well as research materials and reports from the period during which O'Toole served as Director of the AAAA. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - General files, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Advisory Council, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Annual meetings, 1983-1984, 1-2 of 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Annual meetings, 1983-1984 (continued), 3-4 of 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Attitudes on Advertising studies, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors correspondence, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1983-1985, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Budget correspondence, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, general, 1982-1986, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Creative Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Crichton Symposium, 1982, Mar.
    - General files (Box 5)
    - Alfred Seaman Opening Remarks (Box 5)
  - Memos on the depiction of women by American Airlines, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Drug and Alcohol Use, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Educators Seminar, 1984, Mar. 30 (Box 5)
  - Fact Book, 1984, Jun. (Box 5)
  - Government Relations, 1984 (Box 5)
  - How to Handle Public Relations for Your Advertising Agency, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Image of Advertising Committee (Box 6)
    - General files, 1983-1985, 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Meeting files, 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Public Image Report, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Keith Reinhard file, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Institute of Advanced Advertising Studies, 1984, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - International Committee, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Legal Affairs Committee, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Management Dinner, 1984, Nov. (Box 6)
  - Many Faces of Marketing, FTC presentation, 1984 Jan. 18 (Box 6)
  - Media Day, 1983 May 5 (Box 6)
  - New England Senior Management Seminar, 1984 Sept. 17 (Box 6)
  - Operations Committee, 1983-1985, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Operations Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Political Advertising, 1984, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Research Committee, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Story of Advertising Film Committee, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Subliminal Advertising material, 1980-1984, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Submission to the Federal Trade Commission, 1983, undated, 1 of 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Submission to the Federal Trade Commission, 1983, undated (continued), 2 of 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Television Production Costs, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Thirty-Second Split, 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Washington Conference, 1983 Sept., 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Welcome letters, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Western Regional Convention, 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
- Client Files, 1981-1985, 6 boxes
  Contains presentations, correspondence, reports, charts, proofs and tearsheets for domestic and international FCB clients. Also includes files related to the Multinational Business Group, a branch of FCB devoted to increasing international billings. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - General client files (Box 8)
    - Liquor, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Multinational Business Group (MBG)
      - General files, 1982-1985, 1-4 of 8 folders (Box 8)
      - General files, 1982-1985 (continued), 5-8 of 8 folders (Box 9)
      - Board files, 1985 (Box 9)
      - Budgets, 1985 (Box 9)
      - Clients by Product Category by Office, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
      - Directors' files, 1983 (Box 9)
      - Marketing Plan, 1982 (Box 9)
      - MBG Relaunched, 1983 Dec. (Box 9)
    - Multinational Client Classifications, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Multinational Client Expansion Plans, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Multinational Creative Directors, 1984 (Box 9)
    - New Products, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Quarterly Reels, 1982-1984 (Box 9)
  - American Ballet Theatre, Annual Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - American Telephone & Telegraph Co. (AT&T), general files, 1981-1984, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Avis
    - General files, 1982 (Box 10)
    - Media, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Presentation, 1982 Feb. 17 (Box 10)
  - Bermuda Department of Tourism, 1982, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Bristol Myers Co., 1982 (Box 10)
  - British Airways
    - General files, 1981-1983 (Box 10)
    - Presentation book, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Brown & Williamson, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Cable News Network, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Chesebrough-Ponds Creative Presentation, 1982 Sept. 16 (Box 10)
  - Cinzano, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Citibank, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Clairol, 1982-1984 (Box 10)
  - Colgate-Palmolive
    - General files, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
    - Credentials presentation, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Coors, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Corning Glass Works, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Data General International, 1983-1985 (Box 11)
  - Del Monte, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Discover, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Emergence (Paris), 1985 (Box 11)
  - Emery Air Freight Corporation (Worldwide), general files, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Emigrant Savings Bank, general files, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Fotomat, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
  - Frito-Lay, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - General Foods, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - General Mills, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Gillette (Europe)
    - General files, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
    - Hair Care, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Presentation on Facial Scrub Moisturizer Wash Cream, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Silkience
      - European Revitalization, 1985 (Box 11)
      - New Campaign for Silkience, 1984 (Box 11)
      - Silkience Creative Workshop, 1984 (Box 11)
      - Silkience & FCB, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Star Project Concepts, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Gordon's Gin (Renfield), 1982 (Box 11)
  - Guinness, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Hallmark, 1981-1982, 1 of 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Hallmark, 1981-1982 (continued), 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 12)
  - H.J. Heinz Co.
    - General files, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Creative presentation, 1982 Sept. 28 (Box 12)
  - Intergold [South Africa], 1982 (Box 12)
  - International Harvester, 1981 (Box 12)
  - International Paper Company, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Jockey
    - Jockey for Her Campaign, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Presentation, 1983 Jan. 21 (Box 12)
  - Kimberly-Clark, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
  - Knapp Communications, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Kraft, 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Levi-Strauss, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Life Savers, Inc.1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Lipton, Thomas J., 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Loews, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Michelin
    - General files, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Presentation, general, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Presentation, creative, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Miles, Alka-Seltzer
    - General files, 1983 (Box 12)
    - History and Overview, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Minolta, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Nabisco, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Nestlé, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - New York Air, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - Nova Mark, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Noxelle, 1981 (Box 12)
  - N.W. Ayer Co., 1981 (Box 12)
  - Ocean Spray, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Orowheat, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Pepsico Foods, Inc.
    - General files, 1981-1985, 1 of 2 folders (Box 12)
    - General files, 1981-1985 (continued), 2 of 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Advertising Seminar presentation, 1982 Jul. 29 (Box 13)
    - Annual Report, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Pfizer, Inc., 1981 (Box 13)
  - Pitney-Bowes, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
  - Pizza Hut, Inc., 1981-1984 (Box 13)
  - Plough, Inc. (Dr. Scholl's), 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Polaroid, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Procter & Gamble, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Ramada, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Reader's Digest, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
  - Renault [Multinational], 1985 (Box 13)
  - Richardson-Vicks, Inc., 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Rolex, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Rothmans International, 1983 (Box 13)
  - S.C. Johnson & Son, 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - Seagram, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Sears, Roebuck & Co., 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Shulton [Multinational], 1983 (Box 13)
  - Sunkist, 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - Tampax, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Tato-mate, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Unilever, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Union Camp, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Union Underwear, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Warner-Lambert, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Western Electric Company, 1981-1983 (Box 13)
  - Whitehall, 1982-1984 (Box 13)
  - World Airline Policy, 1983 (Box 13)
  - W.R. Grace & Co., 1982 (Box 13)
  - Xerox, 1982-1984 (Box 13)
- Correspondence, 1968-1990 and undated, 10 boxes
  Contains O'Toole's personal and business correspondence, including office-wide memoranda, including those sent by O'Toole while he was company Chairman and several folders of carbon copies. Also includes correspondence O'Toole received upon promotions and anniversaries with the company. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically by title. Folders devoted to FCB clients were moved to the Client Files Series.
  - A, miscellaneous, 1980-1985 (Box 14)
  - Acquisitions
    - General files, 1981, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - NCK-FCB Merger, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Acquisitions and mergers, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Advertising Age, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - Advertising Educational Foundation, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - American Advertising Federation, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - American Ballet Theatre Board of Trustees, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Anniversaries, 1981-1985, 1 of 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Anniversaries, 1981-1985 (continued), 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Associated Communications Companies, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - Awards, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - Awards Policy Memo, 1970 (Box 15)
  - B, miscellaneous, 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Books, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Business Week, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Byoir, Carl & Associates, Inc., 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - C, miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Carroll, Mary Lou, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Chelsea House, 1981-1984 (Box 16)
  - Chicago Office, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Chronological files, 1984-1985, 6 folders (Box 16)
  - C.I.T. Financial Services, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Club 101 at Park, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Commission on National Elections, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Communications, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Cone, Fairfax M., 1968, 1977 (Box 16)
  - Congratulatory, 1982-1985, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Consultants, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Contributions, 1982-1984 (Box 17)
  - Corporate, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Corporate Goals, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Creative Department
    - Creative Directors, domestic, 1974 (Box 17)
    - Home Run correspondence, 1982 (Box 17)
    - Memoranda, 1976-1984 and undated, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - O'Toole memoranda, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - D, miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Dancer, Fitzgerald, Sample, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Deutsch, Shea & Evans, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Doubleday & Co., 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - E, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Encyclopedia, Compton's, 1983 (Box 17)
  - Executive Compensation, 1981 (Box 17)
  - F, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Fallon McElligott Rice, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Fiani & Partners, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Foote, Cone & Belding Corporate, 1982-1983 (Box 17)
  - Frank, Albert, 1981 (Box 17)
  - G, miscellaneous, 1982-1985 (Box 17)
  - Gottesman-Rothchild, Alan, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Grace, W.R., 1982 (Box 17)
  - Grammar Usage, memo by J. O'Toole, 1982 (Box 17)
  - H, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - I, miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 18)
  - Institute of Canadian Advertising, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Interviews, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Invitations, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - J, miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - John & Powers, Inc., 1981 (Box 18)
  - K, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - L, miscellaneous, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Lake Bluff Group, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Lewis, Gilman, & Kynett, 1982-1984 (Box 18)
  - Lorillard
    - General files, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Hearing in Washington, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Los Angeles Office, 1982 (Box 19)
  - M, miscellaneous, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Magazines Canada, 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - McMahon, J., 1981 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1981-1983, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous staff communications, 1982-1984 (Box 19)
  - N, miscellaneous, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Napa Valley Wine Tour, 1981 (Box 19)
  - National Advertising Review Council, 1981 (Box 19)
  - National Bible Week, 1981 (Box 19)
  - New York Office (Box 20)
    - General files, 1981, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 20)